<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog.atom"/>
  <title>Universal Nail Supplies - Blog</title>
  <updated>2019-09-13T16:08:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Universal Nail Supplies</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/how-to-remove-gel-nail-polish-and-acrylic-nails-at-home-step-by-step-guide</id>
    <published>2019-09-13T16:08:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-16T03:17:58-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/how-to-remove-gel-nail-polish-and-acrylic-nails-at-home-step-by-step-guide"/>
    <title>How to remove gel polish and acrylic nails at home</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alen Sarkisyan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Whether you want a new set of gel or acrylic nails, or simply want to remove your false nails, here is a step-by-step cheap and easy removal guide on how to remove false nails from your natural nail bed without damaging your nail!</p>
<strong>STEP 1:</strong><br>
<p>- Wash hands and buff the nail surface (this removes excess oil from the nail)</p>
<p>- if you have long acrylics on, it is highly recommended to clip and shorten your nails before beginning</p>
<p>- product link: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/nail-buffers-180-240-grit-9-5-cm-set-of-11</p>
<p> </p>
<strong>STEP 2:</strong><br>
<p>- Soak a cotton in 100% acetone and wrap cotton on top of your nails with aluminum foil FOR 30 MINUTES!</p>
<p>- product link: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/cnd-shellac-cool-blue-waterless-hand-cleanser</p>
<p> </p>
<strong>STEP 3:</strong><br>
<p>- Remove the foil and scrape off the product from the nail with a cuticle remover</p>
<p>- product link: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/born-pretty-cuticle-pusher-41424-3</p>
<p> </p>
<strong>STEP 4:</strong><br>
<p>- Repeat step 2 for a shorter amount of time (10-15 more minutes) if any product is still left on the nail</p>
<p> </p>
<strong>STEP 5:</strong><br>
<p>- File and buff the nail until excess product is completely off the nail. Be sure to not file too much, as your natural nail may get thinned out and can cause damage.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/bridal-nails-inspo</id>
    <published>2019-08-15T13:54:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-13T16:14:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/bridal-nails-inspo"/>
    <title>Bridal Nails Inspo for your special day!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alen Sarkisyan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Whether you just got engaged, or your wedding is a few weeks away, these bridal nails will give you plenty of inspo for when your special day arrives!</p>
<p>Keep in mind, when making the appointment for your nails:</p>
<ol>
<li>Make sure to book weeks in advance with your nail tech</li>
<li>Let them know what the occasion is so that they know it is important to you as a client</li>
<li>Have photographs ready of the nails you would like (a picture is worth a thousand words!)</li>
<li>Buy and bring the necessary nail tools needed (it is not always guaranteed that they will have your favorite color in stock)</li>
<li>Be prepared to pay a little extra (some nail techs charge more for certain work or designs done)</li>
<li>Do NOT handle any rough work with your hands until your special day is over! (this is to prevent chipping/dulling of the nails)</li>
</ol>
<p>Ready for some beautiful inspo? Take a look below...</p>
<p>1) Here we start with the basic white nails<img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/bridal_large.jpg?v=1565900361" alt="" width="391" height="391"></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/bridal_a8707364-a914-4d7e-a8f4-29a3429a08f3_large.jpg?v=1565900481" alt="" width="393" height="393"></p>
<p>And a flare for the dramatic -- </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/bridal_e0e442b4-8414-4411-85ed-cc798220bc4e_large.jpg?v=1565900532" alt="" width="388" height="388"></p>
<p>2) Here are some ombre/nude looks</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/bridal_2ae2cd1a-3cdb-4483-ac4f-fd8b649b1814_large.jpg?v=1565900586" alt="" width="388" height="388"></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/bridal_113120e1-7212-4258-a1a6-8c9c8cd88146_large.jpg?v=1565900831" alt="" width="390" height="390"></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/bridal_73bc3a91-6b9b-4f55-9413-b0ea45567110_large.jpg?v=1565902364" alt="" width="392" height="392"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/how-to-make-your-nails-grow-faster-and-longer</id>
    <published>2019-06-20T15:14:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-20T13:42:23-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/how-to-make-your-nails-grow-faster-and-longer"/>
    <title>How to Make Your Nails Grow Faster and Longer</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alen Sarkisyan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>One of the biggest issues we are currently struggling with, is figuring out how to grow out healthy, strong, natural nails. Here, we have a short n' sweet list of things you can do to grow your nails out!</p>
<p>1) Keep your cuticles maintained and soft</p>
<p>What a lot of people don't know, is that keeping cuticles healthy is one of the most essentials steps to healthy nail growth. There are plenty of different brands that offer cuticle oils. Below is a link for some of my favorites!</p>
<p>OPI: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/opi-drip-dry-lacquer-drying-drops</p>
<p>Gelish: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/harmony-soak-off-gelish-nail-nourish-cuticle-oil-0-5oz-15ml</p>
<p>Orly: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/orly-gel-fx-vitamin-infused-easy-off-base-coat-0-3-oz-1</p>
<p>Born Pretty: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/born-pretty-nail-brush-black-handle-40682</p>
<p>2) Avoid acrylic nails at all costs!</p>
<p>This may seem like a no-brainer, but some people had to find this out the hard way. Even if you already have thick, healthy nails, acrylic powder and nail tips will do some <strong>major </strong>damage overtime! Not only can the chemicals involved cause allergic reactions to your nails, but they can also break off which can weaken your natural nails and can cause lifting from the nail bed (Yikes).</p>
<p>3) Try Dipping Powder</p>
<p>For those of us whos nails are already on the verge of non-existant, we strongly suggest dipping powder! Dipping powders DO NOT require light-curing or nail tips and nail glue! Your nails can grow out healthy and strong with some color on it too. The best part, is that you can do it right at home with the right kit! Here's a couple of kits we suggest using:</p>
<p>OPI: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/opi-powder-perfection-liquid-essentials-kit</p>
<p>Kiara Sky: https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/kiara-sky-dip-powder-brush-saver-0-5-oz-15-ml-1</p>
<p> </p>
<p>4) Maintain a Healthy Diet</p>
<p>The food you eat plays a huge role in the speed of growth! This is true for hair, skin, and nails too! Add more protein to your diet (lean meat such as chicken or turkey) and biotin (eggs, peanuts). You can also try some over the counter supplements for biotin as well.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/ideas-for-summer-nails</id>
    <published>2019-05-20T13:48:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-20T13:44:48-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/ideas-for-summer-nails"/>
    <title>4 Ideas for Summer Nails</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alen Sarkisyan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>With summer approaching, we're ditching the warm nail colors and going for the brighter look!</p>
<p>Try these 4 designs next time you hit the salon, or are simply bored at home and want to do your nails:</p>
<p><strong>1) Glow In the Dark Nails</strong></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/L-naio-glow-marble_medium.jpg?v=1558376917" alt=""></p>
<p>Next time you visit your favorite nail tech, bring them a bottle of Cre8tion glow in the dark gel. They apply and cure like a regular gel polish, but your nails will look far from regular! If you choose to use dipping powders instead of gel polish, ask your nail tech to try an ombre with the Chisel glow in the dark dipping powders! </p>
<p><strong>2) Neon Nails</strong></p>
<p><strong><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/Neon-Yellow_medium.jpg?v=1558377530" alt=""></strong></p>
<p>Nothing brings attention to nails better than a neon color. We've got you covered. Oranges, greens, pinks, and yellows in neon looks best by the pool side! Take a look at these neon gel collections:</p>
<ul>
<li>https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/harmony-gelish-holiday-2017-thrill-of-the-chill-winter-collection</li>
<li>https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/opi-gelcolor-2019-always-bare-for-you-collection-set-of-6</li>
</ul>
<p>Or, opt for these Chisel dipping powder neon colors:</p>
<ul>
<li>https://universalnailsupplies.com/collections/chisel-neon</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>3) Mermaid Nail Design</strong></p>
<p><strong><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/s-l300_medium.jpg?v=1558384661" alt=""></strong></p>
<p>This design is perfect for when you decide to go to the beach! A mermaid marble design will have people thinking you came straight out of the ocean. Different colored bases will give different results. These decals can be applied at home! Take a look:</p>
<p> https://universalnailsupplies.com/products/1-sheet-rose-gold-3d-nail-art-sticker-set-41138</p>
<p><strong>4) Ombre Nails</strong></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/kds-baby-boomer-acrylic-nude-ombre-nails-powder-buy-baby-boomer-to-retro-nail-design-ideas_medium.jpg?v=1558385070" alt=""></p>
<p>As mentioned above, ombre nails are a good go-to. This happens to be the case for regular acrylic nails as well (not just glow in the dark dip powders). Add a flare to it with beautiful rhinestones!</p>
<ul>
<li>Ombre powders: https://universalnailsupplies.com/collections/chisel-ombre</li>
<li>Rhinestones: https://universalnailsupplies.com/collections/born-pretty-nail-art-wheels</li>
</ul>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/chrome-nail-art-ideas-to-try</id>
    <published>2019-05-02T15:55:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-20T13:43:04-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/chrome-nail-art-ideas-to-try"/>
    <title>Chrome nail art ideas to try!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alen Sarkisyan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Stuck at a salon and not sure what kind of nail art to try? We have the perfect solution that looks good whether it's winter or summer!</p>
<p>Chrome nail art, although has not been around for too long, has taken over the nail art industry! Pearl nails look delicate and beautiful while a mirror shine on your nails can look bold and daring.</p>
<p>With OPI's newest chrome effects intro kit, you can have everything you need to create the look either by yourself, or with your favorite nail tech!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Here's a nice list of a few ideas to try next time you get stuck!</p>
<p>1) A small stripe can create a very soft and delicate look while giving an extra oomph to your nail look! (Bronzed By The Sun)</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/Chrome-Nail-Art-960x1140-2-1_medium.jpg?v=1556836726" alt=""></p>
<p>2) Bold colors can be great for the night life! You're very likely to stand out with purple chrome nails (Amethyst Made The Short List)</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/OPI_Chrome1111_sq_0_medium.jpg?v=1556837486" alt=""></p>
<p>3) Summer is just around the corner, so try a blue/green look to kick start the nail trends of 2019 (Blue Plate Special)</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2553/3966/files/5c7f25ee14f3ba06fee4aca581c866c0_medium.jpg?v=1556837564" alt=""></p>
<p>We know you may not have time to head on over to your local nail salon, so here's a how-to video that we'll drop here for you in case you'd like to try these at home! Remember, all of the supplies you need for any of these applications can be found here, through the search bar!</p>
<p><iframe width="723" height="407" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lUEuOhSYMdc?list=PLQJUg0LNqNatduIgpSgRzrahwWenyZkHE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/acrylic-nails-healthy-alternative</id>
    <published>2019-05-02T15:22:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-20T14:00:19-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://universalnailsupplies.com/blogs/blog/acrylic-nails-healthy-alternative"/>
    <title>Acrylic nails healthy alternative!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alen Sarkisyan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Unhealthy nails. We have all been there. With new products always on the market, it's hard to weigh your options and figure out the pros and cons. That's why we're here!</p>
<p>Traditional Acrylic Nails require the use of many chemicals and dangerous application tactics. Not only are products such as powders, liquids, nail glue, and tips being applied to your nail, but you also have a nail drill filing down your natural nails to its core before application. And don't get us started on what happens when you accidentally break one of those beautiful, costly nails.</p>
<p><strong> Here are some pros of acrylics nails:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>more durable than regular manicure</li>
<li>most nail techs have mastered the application</li>
<li>low-cost (compared to gel application)</li>
<li>can prevent bad habit of nail biting</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Here are some cons of acrylic nails:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>can damage natural nail</li>
<li>can cause allergic reactions</li>
<li>can cause natural nail to lift from its nail bed (ouch)</li>
<li>requires professional application and is not recommended to try at home</li>
<li>requires filing the natural nail down with every new set</li>
<li>strong odors/dust </li>
<li>application takes at least 45 minutes (up to 2 hours)</li>
</ul>
<p>We're here to introduce <strong>Aprés Nail Gel-X Gel Extension System</strong> -- the world's first and only soft gel nail extension system!</p>
<p>The soft gel extension system is much better for a number of reasons. The tips are made from cutting edge soft gel formulas. With the tips already in shape and ready to use, there is no need for filing or shaping (unless you would prefer to do so). Application is a breeze with step by step instructions (so easy you can do it at home with the right tools). </p>
<p><strong>Here are some pros of Aprés Gel-X Sytem:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>does not cause damage to natural nails</li>
<li>does not require filing/drilling natural nail</li>
<li>does not require filing/shaping extension tip</li>
<li>tip covers entire nail (no need to add extra powder/liquid)</li>
<li>with enough practice, application can be as fast as 10 minutes</li>
<li>simple and harmless removal</li>
<li>simple step by step instructions ensure easy application</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Here are some cons of Aprés Gel-X System:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>may be hard to locate salons that have mastered the technique</li>
<li>may require LED/UV light (although the kit does come with a 2W mini light!)</li>
<li>may be more expensive as opposed to the traditional acrylic nails</li>
</ul>
<p>All in all, if you are looking for a healthier and more efficient alternative to traditional acrylic nails, we highly recommend trying this product! See a how-to video below and be amazed at the easy breezy application!</p>
<p>GEL-X HOW TO:</p>
<p><iframe width="806" height="453" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O_YcsKDUWkk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
